舰长日志，星历1533.6
Captain's log, stardate 1533.6.
我们受命向运输船心大星号靠拢
Now manoeuvring to come alongside cargo vessel Antares.
该船的船长和大副正向我舰传送中
Its captain and first officer are beaming over to us
随行的还有一位不寻常的乘客
with an unusual passenger.
好了，士官长，开始物化
All right, chief. Begin materialisation.
拉马舰长，我是寇克舰长
Captain Ramart, I'm Captain Kirk.
- 这是我的领航员汤姆·奈里斯 - 你好
- This is my navigator, Tom Nellis. - How do you do?
- 你好 - 这位年轻人就是船难生还者，查理
- How do you do? - This is our young castaway, Charlie.
全名查理·埃文斯，这是他的档案
Charlie Evans. His dossier.
埃文斯先生
Mr. Evans.
我们对你早有耳闻，欢迎登舰
We've heard a great deal about you. Welcome aboard.
查理是个好孩子，我们非常荣幸找到了他
Wonderful boy, Charlie. We felt honoured to find him.
有他在舰上的日子很愉快，真的很愉快
It's been a pleasure having him. Why, it's been a great pleasure.
- 他所学的知识… - 绝对是
- The things that he's learned-- - Absolutely.
想想这孩子几乎一个人在那星球生活了这么久
To think this boy's spent practically his whole life alone on that planet,
无人幸存，只能从几卷微型卡带里学东西
everyone killed, just a few micro-tapes to learn from.
船上有多少我这样的人？
How many humans like me on this ship?
就像太空里的一座城市那么多，查理
Like a whole city in space, Charlie.
这艘星舰上有四百多船员，对吧，舰长？
Over 400 in the crew of a starship, aren't there, captain?
确切地说是四百二十八名
Four hundred and twenty-eight, to be exact.
舰长，需要什么帮助吗？药品，粮食补给？
Is there anything we can do for you, captain? Medical supplies, provisions?
几百个
Hundreds.
都是像我这样的人
All human like me.
太激动了
That's exciting.
- 是用这个词吗？ - 非常好，就是这个词
- Is that the right word? - That's perfect. It’s the exact word.
瞧见没？
You see?
我们非常乐意带着查理一起航行
We'd like to keep Charlie with us,
但和他关系最亲密的健在亲属在5号殖民地
but with his closest living relatives on Colony V
- 而且你们会路过那里，所以… - 我想现在就参观你的星舰
- and your vessel going that way, why-- - I'd like to see your ship now.
全部，所有的人和东西
All of it. The people and everything.
你一直打断我们，埃文斯先生
You keep interrupting, Mr. Evans.
这么做可不对
That's considered wrong.
对不起
I'm sorry.
先生们，我们有大量的娱乐影音带
We have a large supply of entertainment tapes, gentlemen.
不了，舰长，我们行程颇紧
No, we've a tight schedule to make, captain.
- 我们只有二十人，我们会搞定的 - 这一定是太空第一艘…
- Just 20 of us. We're making out fine. - This must be a space first.
- 什么也不需要的舰船 - 真的不需要
- A ship that doesn't need anything. - Nothing.
连蜥蜴酒也不要吗？
Not even Saurian brandy?
不必了，谢谢，很高兴拜访至此
We're fine, thank you. Pleasant journey.
谢谢
Thank you.
兰德文书，这位是查理·埃文斯
Yeoman Rand, this is Charles Evans.
带他去他的舱房，然后把他的档案放到麦考伊医生的办公室
Show him to his quarters and drop his records off at Dr. McCoy's office,
- 如果你愿意的话 - 好的，长官
- if you will. - Yes, sir.
请跟我来
Come with me, please.
你是女生吗？
Are you a girl?
她是女生吗？
Is that a girl?
她是女生
That's a girl.
宇宙，最后的边疆
space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：马田的心事，kmdangdangli，吴涵知
校对：心痕依，Micezhang，xjCGI
第一季第二集
神秘人查理
舰长日志，星历1533.7
Captain's log, stardate 1533.7.
我们迎来了一位不寻常的乘客
We have taken aboard an unusual passenger
要把他送去阿尔法5号殖民地
for transport to Colony Alpha V.
查理·埃文斯
Charles Evans,
十四年前一艘运输船坠毁后的唯一幸存者
the sole survivor of a transport crash 14 years ago.
他不仅活了下来，且自三岁起就独自生活
A child, alone from age 3, has not only survived,
现已成长为一名智聪体健的少年
but has grown to intelligent, healthy adolescence.
跟我说说
Tell me,
那艘船上的浓缩食物供给撑不过14年
the ship's supply of food concentrates couldn't have lasted 14 years.
后来，我就找周围生长的东西吃
After that, I found other things to eat just growing around.
靠船上的卡带就学会说话了？
And you learned to talk by just listening to the ship's tapes?
记忆资料库还有用，他们和我说一句，我就回一句
The memory banks still worked. They talked to me, and I talked back.
你得了四分
You're 4-0.
四分？
Four?
四分就是满分
Four-0, 100 percent.
身体倍棒
Sound of wind and limb.
- 那个舰长，叫寇克… - 怎么了？
- That captain... Kirk? - Yeah?
他为什么叫我埃文斯先生？
Why does he call me Mr. Evans?
因为那是你的名字
Because that's your name.
他不是…
He's not...
- 他和拉马舰长不同 - 不同
- Well, he isn't like Captain Ramart. - Oh, no.
寇克舰长可是独一无二的，查理
Captain Kirk is one of a kind, Charlie.
你喜欢我吗？
Do you like me?
为什么不？
Why not?
有些…
Some...
其他的船员
The other ship.
他们不喜欢我
They didn't like me.
我尽力了
I tried.
我在努力让大家喜欢我
I'm trying to make people like me.
- 我想要他们喜欢我 - 多数十七岁的孩子都这么想
- I want them to like me. - Most 17-year-olds do.
来，我们走，带你去看看你的舱房
Come on, let's go. I'll show you to your quarters.
我去把设备收好，娱乐室见
Hey, I'll put the equipment away. See you in the Rec Room, huh?
- 就这么定了，朋友 - 好吧
- You got a deal, friend. - All right.
你好
Hello.
我给你带了礼物
I brought you a present.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
非常感谢，但是…我得去值班了
I really appreciate it, but-- But I have to go. I’m on duty.
- 你喜欢这种吗？ - 喜欢，我…
- Do you like that kind? - Yes, I--
这是我的最爱
It's my favourite.
你从哪里弄来的，船上的仓储里没有这个
Where did you get it? They don't have any in the ship's stores.
送你的礼物
It's a present.
我知道，但是你从哪里…
I know, but where did--?
我快迟到了，查理，我真得走了
Gee, I'm late, Charlie. I really have to go.
你能留下来陪我说会儿话吗？
Can't you stay and talk a little while?
我会在1400时下班
Look, I’m off duty at 14:00.
你去三号甲板的六号娱乐室找我吧
Why don't you join me in Recreation Room 6, Deck 3.
就这么定了，朋友
You've got a deal, friend.
查理
Charlie!
我以为…
I thought...
别生气，我并不…
Don't be angry. I didn't--
- 我想… - 查理，你…
- I wanted... - Charlie, you...
你不能随便拍女孩儿的…
You just don't go around slapping girls on the...
这次算了，但别再这么做了
It's okay, but just don't do it again.
别生气
Don't be angry.
听着，去和寇克舰长或者麦考伊医生谈谈刚才的事吧
Look, why don't you tell Captain Kirk or Dr. McCoy what you did,
他们会向你解释清楚的，好吗？
and they'll explain it to you, okay?
- 我会的 - 好吧
- I will. - Okay.
告诉我，如果那有塔索斯人，他为什么要说谎？
But tell me, what reason would he have to lie if there are Thasians?
这个问题很有意思
That is a very intriguing question.
舰长，传感器显示本象限无干扰
Scanners show no disturbances in this quadrant, captain.
好的，麦考伊医生，史波克正在制定…
Good. Dr. McCoy, Mr. Spock is working out--
- 打扰一下，舰长，这是状况报告 - 谢谢
- Excuse me, captain, status report. - Thank you.
他正在为查理·埃文斯设计培训项目
He's working out a training programme for Charlie Evans.
包括地球史，以及他的种族背景之类的
Earth history, his own background, that sort of thing.
我倒是希望你能从医学角度
I'd like you to give him the necessary medical orientation
给予他一些必要的指导，关于…
on the problems of...
关于青春期
...adolescence.
你不觉得你更适合扮演父亲这个角色？
Don't you think it'd be better for a father image like you?
- 他已经一切向你看齐了 - 这事归你了，老骨头
- He already looks up to you. - The job is yours, Bones.
阿谀奉承会使你一事无成
Flattery will get you nowhere.
医生，那孩子就一点都没提到塔索斯人？
Doctor, didn't the boy make any reference at all to Thasians?
你相信塔索斯人仍以某种形式
Do you believe the legend
存活于那颗星球之上的传说吗？
that Thasians still exist on that planet in some form?
实际上，查理的存在就是塔索斯星
Charlie's very existence proves, in fact,
存在某种智慧生命体的有力证据
there must be some intelligent form of life on Thasus.
仅靠自己他不可能生存下来
He could not possibly have survived alone.
船上的食物一年半载就消耗殆尽了
The ship's food would have been exhausted in a year or so.
那时，他可以靠水果蔬菜维生
By which time, he would've been eating fruits, vegetables.
对塔索斯星的探测表明，那里几乎没有可食用的植物
Probes of Thasus indicate very little edible plant life.
史波克先生，我们都知道探测器出过错
And probes have been known to be wrong, Mr. Spock.
医生，你是理智发言还是感情用事呐？
Doctor, are you speaking scientifically or emotionally?
先生们，事实是，这孩子就在这活着，而且需要我们帮助
Gentlemen. The fact is, the boy is here and he's alive and he needs our help.
而且需要指导，吉姆，他需要一位父亲的榜样
And he needs a guide and he needs a father image, Jim.
我指望着你的聪明才智能去解决这一问题
I'll depend on your astute abilities to supply him with that.
给他找一个也行
Or find him one.
抱歉，我是不是又打扰到你了？
I'm sorry. I did it again, didn't I?
#在星舰进取号上
Oh, on the starship Enterprise
#有一个伪装成撒旦模样的人
There's someone Who's in Satan's guise
#他那恶魔的耳朵，邪恶的双眼
whose devil ears and devil eyes
#能将你鲜活的心生生挖出胸膛
Could rip your heart from you
#目光触碰，他便将你催眠
At first his look could hypnotise
#轻柔相抚，他便将你撕裂
And then his touch would barbarize
#他的异族之爱会深深地把你伤害
His alien love could victimize
#将你鲜活的心生生挖出胸膛
And rip your heart from you
#所以飞天女
And that's why female astronauts
#美丽的飞天女
Oh, very female astronauts
#恐惧而又忧愁的等待
Wait terrified and overwrought
#皆因了解面具下的他
To find what he will do
#太空中的女孩要小心
Oh, girls in space be wary
#小心啊，小心啊
Be wary, be wary
#太空中的女孩要万分小心
Girls in space be wary
#他是一个谜
We know not what he'll do.
再来一曲
One more time.
#在那太空中的某颗星上
Now, from a planet out in space
#有位不一般的少年
There comes a lad Not commonplace
#只为找寻他的初恋
A-seeking out his first embrace
#你就是他要找的人
He's saving it for you
#查理是我们的新甜心
Oh, Charlie's our new darling
#我们的甜心，甜心
Our darling, our darling
#查理是我们的新甜心
Charlie's our new darling
#他是一个谜
We know not what he'll do
我给你看些东西？
Want to see something?
翻牌
Turn them over.
你是怎么办到的？
Well, how did you do that?
我很会玩纸牌魔术
I can do a lot of card tricks.
心大星号上的一个人教我的
One of the men on the Antares showed me.
难以置信
I don't believe it.
今天是地球上的感恩节
On Earth today, it's Thanksgiving.
如果船员不得不吃合成的肉卷，我希望它看上去像只火鸡
If the crew has to eat synthetic meat loaf, I want it to look like turkey.
- 查理 - 舰长
- Charlie. - Captain?
- 什么事？ - 我有些事要问你
- Yes. - I'm supposed to ask you something.
为什么我不该…？
Why shouldn't I...?
- 我不知道怎么说 - 直白的说出来就行
- I don't know how to explain it. - Say it right out, that usually works.
我在走廊里看见…
Well, in the corridor, I saw...
当贾尼丝…兰德文书
When Janice... When Yeoman Rand was...
我这么拍她了，她很反感
Well, I did that to her, and she didn't like it.
- 她说你会向我解释清楚 - 我？
- She said you'd explain it to me. - Me?
我明白了
I see. Well...
查理，有些事情不能对女士做的…
There are things you can do with a lady, Charlie, that you...
不能拍打女士
Well, there's no right way to hit a woman.
我是说，男人拍打男人没事
I mean, man-to-man is one thing,
但是男人拍打女人
but man and woman,
这是…
it's...
是…
Is...
就是另外一回事了
Well, it's another thing.
- 你明白吗？ - 不明白
- Do you understand? - I don't know.
- 寇克舰长 - 稍等
- Captain Kirk. - Excuse me.
我是寇克
Kirk here.
心大星号舰长拉马正在D频道等候
Captain Ramart of the Antares is on D channel.
我马上到舰桥
I'm on my way to the bridge now.
- 能一起去吗？ - 不能
- Can I come? - I don't think so.
- 我不会妨碍你们 - 好吧
- I won't get in the way. - Okay.
心大星号，能否加强信号？
Can you boost your power, Antares?
我们几乎接收不到你们的传输信号
We're barely reading your transmission.
进取号，我们已经满额输出了
We are at full output, Enterprise.
我必须和寇克舰长通话
I must speak to Captain Kirk.
我是寇克，拉马舰长
Kirk here, Captain Ramart.
舰长，好不容易联系上你，我得警告…
Captain, we're just barely in range. I've got to warn--
重建通信
Reestablish contact.
- 他们没在发射信号 - 再试试
- They're not transmitting. - Well, try.
那艘星舰构造不太好
It wasn't very well-constructed.
用我们的探测传感器扫描…
Sweep the area of the Antares transmission
- 心大星号发出通讯的区域，史波克先生 - 收到，舰长
- with our probe scanners, Mr. Spock. - Affirmative, captain.
查理，你认为心大星出事了吗？
Do you think something happened to the Antares, Charlie?
我不知道
I don't know.
舰长，传感器探测到了些许残骸
Picking up some debris on our scanners, captain.
那心大星号呢？
What about the Antares?
那些就是心大星号的残骸
The debris is what's left of the Antares.
- 寇克舰长，这里是星舰厨房 - 我是寇克
- Captain Kirk, from ship's galley. - Kirk here.
长官，之前我将肉卷放置在烤箱中
Sir, I put meat loaf in the ovens.
现在它们变成了火鸡，真正的火鸡
There's turkeys in there now. Real turkeys.
主厨，你是不是…？
Chief, have you...?
舰长日志，星历1535.8
Captain's log, stardate 1535.8.
地球联邦空间探测总署已经宣布了
UESPA headquarters notified of the mysterious loss
科学探测船心大星号的神秘失踪 （心大星号是一艘多用途太空船，可用于运输、科学测量等）
of science-probe vessel Antares.
舰长，你的心思不在这盘棋上
Your mind is not on the game, captain.
将军
Check.
在想心大星号？
The Antares?
二十人的测量船，全部罹难
A survey ship with 20 men aboard lost.
原因不详
No reason.
显然拉马舰长没有意识到丝毫危险
Obviously Captain Ramart was not aware of any trouble.
我想不通
I can't figure it.
眼下我更担心的
My own concern is more immediate.
是那个男孩
The boy.
通常我能理解你的意思，但这次…
I can usually follow you, Mr. Spock, but this time...
似乎他比我们更早知道心大星号的结局
He seemed to know what happened to the Antares before we did.
证据确凿，再下结论，史波克
I'd call that a pretty long reach for evidence, Mr. Spock.
请进，查理
Come in, Charlie.
再次
And again.
将军
Check.
你输了
Checkmate.
你这种没有章法的棋路
Your illogical approach to chess
有时的确厉害，舰长
does have its advantages on occasion, captain.
我下棋都靠灵感
I prefer to call it inspired.
就算是吧，反正你赢了
As you wish. At any rate, the game is yours.
会下棋吗，查理？
Do you play chess, Charlie?
哦…我在心大星号上见他们玩过
Oh, I-- I watched them play on the Antares.
能试试吗？
Can I try?
那就和这位象棋大师杀一盘吧
I place you in the hands of our chess master.
三维象棋的游戏规则
The principles of three-dimensional chess
基于数学，查理，白棋放这
are basically mathematic, Charlie. You put the white here,
- 黑棋在第二层 - 我知道怎么玩，开始吧
- and the black on the secondary level. - I know what it is. Let's play.
那好吧
Very well.
这可是个错着，查理
That was a mistake, Charlie.
我没走错
No, it wasn't.
你输了
Checkmate.
我没输
No, it isn't.
失陪一下
If you'll excuse me.
哦，查理，我正找你
Oh, Charlie, I was looking for you.
这位是蒂娜·劳顿，三级文书
I'd like you to meet Tina Lawton, yeoman, third class.
- 查理·埃文斯 - 你好，查理
- Charlie Evans. - Hello, Charlie.
我觉得你一定想认识些同龄人
I thought you might enjoy meeting someone your own age.
能和你聊聊吗？单独
Can I talk to you? Alone.
查理，蒂娜她…
Charlie, Tina is...
失陪了，别的地方总会欢迎我的
Excuse me. I must be wanted somewhere.
你刚真是…
That was...
太粗鲁，太不适宜了
That was rude and completely uncalled for.
但我不需要她，我只想和你聊天
But I don't need her. I wanna talk to you.
这不是借口
But that's no excuse.
你得学会尊重人
You'd better learn that right now.
学会跟人相处，查理，你不再是一个人了
You have to live with people, Charlie. You're not alone anymore.
但她没你…
But she's not as...
她不…
She doesn't...
她和你不同
She's not the same.
她不像你
Not like you.
她…她只是个女孩
She's-- She's just a girl.
而你…
You're...
你闻上去如女孩般甜美
You smell like a girl.
可舰上的其他女孩，她们…
All the other girls on the ship, they...
她们和蒂娜一样
They look just like Tina.
只有你最特别
You're the only one who looks like you.
你懂我意思吗？
You can understand, can't you?
你知道那种寸步不离
You know about being with somebody?
想和一个人在一起的感觉吗？
Wanting to be?
若我拥有整个宇宙
If I had the whole universe...
我就把它献给你
...I'd give it to you.
当我见到你，我…
When I see you, I...
一股冲动在心中燃烧
I feel like I'm hungry.
如此地
All over.
强烈
Hungry.
你知道那感觉吗？
Do you know how that feels?
他说啥？！
He what?
我很犹豫该不该找你谈
I wasn't sure I should talk to you about this.
文书，查理是个17岁的男孩
Yeoman, Charlie's a 17-year-old boy.
- 正是，他还… - 我和他谈过他拍打你的事了
- Exactly. And he's... - I talked to him about the swat.
不是那事
It's not that.
舰长，我了解那种眼神
Captain, I've seen the look before,
若置之不理
and if something isn't done,
我迟早会伤他的心
sooner or later, I'm gonna have to hurt him.
叫他别来找我了
Tell him to leave me alone.
他还小，对他不好
And that wouldn't be good for him right now.
他一来就爱上我
You see, I'm his first crush,
我便是他的初恋
his first love,
- 他的第一次… - 知道了，文书
- and his first-- - Yes, yeoman.
我找他谈，我会处理的
I'll talk to him. I'll look into it.
谢谢你，长官
Thank you, sir.
进来，查理
Come in, Charlie.
查理…
Charlie...
查理，你知道这棋子怎么了吗？
Charlie, do you know anything about this chess piece?
注意到这颗棋
Did you notice anything peculiar in them...
- 同之前有何不同吗？ - 没有，长官
- ...when we were using them? - No, sir.
- 没别的事了吧？ - 不…还有
- Is that all? - No. No, no.
坐吧
Sit down.
查理，17岁不仅仅是个数字
Charlie, being 17 is more than how many years you've lived.
还代表着别的含义
It's a whole other thing.
麦考伊医生也许解释过生理的变化
Dr. McCoy could probably explain the biological conditions.
那我…我们就说个具体的
Well, let's-- Let's use a specific.
兰德文书是个女的
Yeoman Rand is a woman.
- 我不会再拍打她了 - 不光是那件事
- I won't hit her like that anymore. - No, there's more to it than that.
不管我说什么，做什么都是错
Everything I do or say is wrong.
我讨人厌，我不懂规矩
I'm in the way. I don't know the rules.
我认真学，不管再努力还是一错再错！
When I learn something and try to do it, suddenly, I’m wrong!
- 冷静点，慢慢说 - 我不知道自己是什么
- Now, wait a minute. Wait a minute. - I don't know what I am
该成为什么
or what I’m supposed to be
甚至到底是谁
or even who.
为何我心里总是很难受？
I don't know why I hurt so much inside all the time.
会好的，相信我
You'll live. Believe me.
你的感受很正常
There's nothing wrong with you that hasn't gone wrong
凡是男人都会经历
with every other human male since the model first came out.
要是你中意某人，会怎么做？
What if you care for someone? What do you do?
你得慢慢来
You go slow.
你得…
You...
温柔地
You be gentle.
我的意思是
I mean, it's...
感情不是单方的，不能光顾你的感受
It's not a one-way street, you know. How you feel and that's all.
也要看对方的感受
It's how the girl feels too.
强扭的瓜不甜，查理
Don't press, Charlie.
若对方也喜欢你
If the girl feels anything for you at all,
自然会告诉你
you'll know it.
明白了吗？
Do you understand?
你是说贾尼丝…
You don't think Jan--
文书…
Yeo--
- 她会爱上我的！ - 你们不合适，查理
- She could love me! - She's not the girl, Charlie.
你们年龄悬殊，这是其一
The years are wrong, for one thing.
还有其他原因
And there are other things.
- 她会的 - 不，查理
- She can. - No, Charlie.
- 她会的 - 不可能！
- She is. - No!
那我听你的，我会温柔的
But if I did what you said, if I was gentle.
查理，在这宇宙你可以拥有很多
There are a million things in this universe you can have,
也有很多东西一辈子注定不能拥有
and there are a million things you can't have.
现实就这么残酷，除了面对，别无选择
It's no fun facing that, but that's the way things are.
那接下来我该怎么办？
Well, then what am I going to do?
咬紧牙，活下去
Hang on tight and survive.
人人都这样
Everybody does.
- 你就不是 - 每个人，查理，包括我
- You don't. - Everybody, Charlie. Me too.
我努力了…
I'm trying...
可就是不得要领
...but I don't know how.
- 我是寇克 - 报告
- Kirk here. - You asked to be notified
航向即将调整，长官
when we were to make our course adjustments, sir.
让史波克大副负责此事
Ask Mr. Spock to see to it.
查理，跟我来
Charlie, come on with me.
倒向地面来缓冲你摔倒时的冲力
Gotta slap the floor to absorb the energy when you fall.
试试吧
Go ahead, try it.
凡事得多练，查理，再来
Like everything else it takes practise, Charlie. Try again.
很好，好多了
Good. Much better.
接下来我会示范一个肩膀滚翻
Here, now I'll show you a shoulder roll.
试试
Try that.
我不想
I don't wanna do that.
- 你这样我会教不好… - 我不想做
- Well, it makes it hard to teach you-- - I don't wanna do that.
好吧，查理，今天就学到这
All right, Charlie, lesson's over for today.
你答应教我格斗的
You were gonna teach me how to fight.
你得先学会跌倒时的自我保护
You have to learn to protect yourself from the fall before I do that.
我再教你自我防卫
It's more than just teaching you how to defend yourself.
查理，我想让你学会…
Charlie, I want you to learn--
查理
Charlie.
嗨，山姆，配合我摔几个？
Hey, Sam, let me borrow you for a couple of easy throws, huh?
- 好啊 - 看好了，查理
- All right. - Watch this, Charlie.
没那么坏，是不？现在换我摔他
Wasn't so bad, was it? Now I'll throw him.
准备好，山姆
Here we go, Sam.
看上去很难
That looks hard.
加油，查理，试试
Come on, Charlie, try it.
好样的
Attaboy. That's good.
这不难吧？
Wasn't so bad, was it?
- 别笑我 - 别在意，查理
- Don't laugh at me. - Cool off, Charlie.
不要取笑我！
Don't laugh at me!
查理
Charlie.
他不该那样对我
He shouldn't have done that.
取笑别人是不对的
It's not nice to laugh at people.
他怎么了，查理？
What happened to him, Charlie?
他不在了
He's gone.
回答我的问题
That's no answer.
他不在了！
He's gone!
我不想这样，是他逼我的
I didn't mean to do that. He made me do it.
他笑我
He laughed at me.
- 舰桥 - 我是寇克
- Bridge. - Kirk here.
这里需要两名安全人员，尽快
Two men from Security on the double.
- 收到 - 你要对我做什么？
- Affirmative. - What are you going to do to me?
待在你的舱房，面壁思过
I'm confining you to quarters. I want you to stay there.
我不会让他们伤害我
I won't let them hurt me.
- 我会让他们也消失 - 他们不会伤害你，查理
- I'll make them go away too. - They won't hurt you, Charlie.
他们会送你回舱房，查理，跟他们回去
They'll take you to your quarters, Charlie. Go with them.
不！
No!
回你的舱房去
Go to your quarters.
他刚才想伤害我
He was going to hurt me.
回你的舱房，否则我亲自把你拎回去
Go to your quarters, or I'll pick you up and carry you there.
我不会让你得逞
I won't let you.
那就别怪我不客气，查理
That's your choice, Charlie.
我不会让他们伤害我
I won't let them hurt me.
他们不会的
They won't hurt you.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk?
我是寇克
Kirk here.
安全部报告，所有相位武器都消失了
Security reports that all phaser weapons have disappeared.
需要重复吗，舰长？
Shall I repeat, captain?
不，我听清了
No, I heard you.
让麦考伊医生和史波克大副到简报室见我
Have Dr. McCoy and Mr. Spock meet me in the Briefing Room.
据记载，塔索斯人[非实体生物族群，居住在塔索斯星球]
Thasians have been referred to in our records
能让物体嬗变
as having the power to transmute objects
或消失
or render substances invisible.
这虽只是个传说
It has generally been regarded as legend,
但查理似乎的确拥有这种能力
but Charlie does seem to possess this same power.
难道查理并非人类而是塔索斯人？
What chance is there that Charlie isn't an Earth being, that he's a Thasian?
我并不这么想
No, I don't think so.
除非它们和地球人一样
Not unless they're exactly like earthlings.
他手指和脚趾的发育
The development of his fingers and toes
和同龄地球人一模一样
exactly matches the present development of man's on Earth.
- 有道理 - 但不论他是什么
- Agreed. - But whatever he is,
他的能力我们已有所了解
we have some idea of the power he has.
我亲眼目睹他在健身房的所作所为
I know what I saw him do in the gymnasium.
考虑到一个家庭对一个普通青少年的影响
Considering the effect a normal adolescent has on a home,
查理，所具备…
Charlie, with the power he has...
暴躁的脾气，因为他还不明世事
Short-tempered, because he doesn't understand.
他既冲动又渴望，不会走就想跑
He needs, he wants. Nothing happens fast enough.
心大星号的毁灭可能和他有关
The probability is, he's responsible for the destruction of the Antares,
因为他还不懂得尊重生命
which would indicate a total disregard for human life.
他不会明白生命的意义，他就是个孩子
He doesn't understand what life is. He's a boy.
那如何对付这个孩子，吉姆？
Well, what do we do with this boy, Jim?
- 关他的禁闭？ - 这还远远不够，医生
- How do we keep him caged up? - It goes even further than that, doctor.
我们没法带他去5号殖民地
We can't take him with us to Earth Colony V.
你能想象他在一个开放、正常的环境里做出什么吗？
Can you imagine what he'd do in an open, normal environment?
我循循善诱，用心倾听
I've talked with him. I've listened to him.
他身体成熟，可心智稚嫩
He's a boy in a man's body, trying to be an adult,
正值青春期，却一心想做个大人
with the adolescent in him getting in the way.
他可怕的能力能置人于死地
And with a weapon in him, which could destroy you or anyone,
他能杀死这艘星舰上的任何人
anywhere on this ship.
好在眼下他停住了
Well, for the moment, he's stopped.
- 他很崇拜你，吉姆 - 我也这么想
- You're an authority he respects, Jim. - Agreed.
只有你才能说服得了他
The struggle must remain between you and him.
万一我们之中有人插手这件事…
Should any of us interfere...
他说你想问我点事
You wanted to ask me something, he said.
查理，心大星号的事是不是你干的？
Are you responsible for what happened to the Antares, Charlie?
- 怎么了？ - 回答我
- Why? - Answer me.
是的
Yes.
在能源反应堆的防护罩上有一块变形了的折流档板
There was a warped baffle plate on the shield of their energy pile.
我让它消失了
I made it go away.
迟早都会爆炸的
It would have blown up anyway.
而且他们对我一点也不好！
Well, they weren't nice to me!
他们想要把我赶走
They wanted to get rid of me.
但现在办不到了
They don't now.
那我们呢，查理？
What about us, Charlie?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们落入青春期少年手里了
We're in the hands of an adolescent.
上尉，接5号殖民地
Lieutenant, raise Colony V.
- 我要直接和他们的总督通话 - 遵命，长官
- I want to speak to the governor. - Yes, sir.
领航员，制定路线，离开5号殖民地
Navigator, lay in a course away from Colony V.
- 争取时间 - 是，长官
- Buy me some time. - Yes, sir.
史波克，让医生尽快过来
Spock, get the doctor up here on the double.
严重吗？
How bad is it?
长官，我还好
I think it's all right, sir.
长官，那块控制板不可能这样无缘无故的短路
Sir, there's no reason for that panel to cross-circuit like that.
不到15分钟前，我还亲自检查过的
I checked it over myself not 15 minutes ago.
舰长！
Captain!
长官，我无法在控制板输入航线坐标
I can't feed any course coordinates into the panel, sir.
- 它不接受任何航线改动了 - 长官，船舵也没有反应
- It rejects the course change. - Helm doesn't respond either, sir.
史波克，你那边有读数吗？
Mr. Spock, you getting any readings on your instruments?
是的，长官，有一个…
Yes, sir. There's a--
老虎！老虎！黑夜的森林中
Tiger, tiger, burning bright
燃烧着的煌煌的火光 （来自威廉·布莱克的《老虎》）
In the forest of the night
- 史波克？ - 我正要…
- Mr. Spock? - I'm trying to--
脑海环绕着土星，游荡在火星的红色之路
Saturn rings around my head Down a road that's Martian red
舰长，你想要改变航线吗？
You're trying to change course, captain.
你不能那么做，我想快点到5号殖民地去
You can't do that. I want to get to Colony V as soon as we can.
让通讯发射器恢复正常
Release the transmitter.
你用不着听那些子空间的杂音
You don't need all that subspace chatter.
这里发生了什么事儿？
What's going on here?
史波克叫我到舰桥来
Spock calls me to the bridge
- 话还没说完就开始吟什么诗了… - 照看一下她，麦考伊
- and then goes into poetry. - See to her, doctor.
从前一个阴郁的子夜，我独自沉思，慵懒疲竭 (来自爱伦坡《乌鸦》)
Once upon a midnight dreary, while I pondered, weak and weary
好样的，尖耳朵先生
Very nice, Mr. Ears.
我可以让他做任何事，转圈，大笑，所有事情
Oh, I can make him do anything. Whirl around, laugh, anything.
够了，查理
That's enough, Charlie.
你不觉得他很好笑吗？我觉得他好笑极了
Don't you think he's funny? I think he's funny.
别动我的船员
Leave my crew alone.
吉姆，很快他就会抗拒你了
Jim, he'll soon reach a point where he won't back down.
我知道
I know.
查理，怎么了？
Charlie, what's wrong?
我有样东西要给你
I have something for you.
你最喜欢粉色，对吧？
Pink is your favourite, isn't it?
你不能不敲门就进别人房间
You don't walk into a room without knocking.
贾尼丝，别再对我锁上你的门，我爱你
Don't ever lock your door on me again, Janice. I love you.
我想锁就锁
I'll lock it when I please.
你到底想要什么？
What is it you want, anyway?
你
You.
我只想对你好
I only want to be nice to you.
只要你告诉我，我什么都可以给你
I can give you anything. Just-- Just tell me.
我要你出去
I want you to get out.
- 我只是想对你好而已 - 出去，查理
- I only want to be nice to you. - Get out, Charlie.
- 史波克 - 我说的已经很清楚了
- Spock. - I can't make it any plainer than that.
我爱你
I love you.
你根本不知道这句话的意思
You don't know what the word means.
- 那你教我 - 不！
- Then show me. - No!
查理
Charlie.
她为什么这么做？
Why did she do that?
我爱她…
I loved her...
…但她对我一点也不好
...but she wasn't nice at all.
你们对我也不好
What you did wasn't nice either.
但我仍然需要你，舰长
But I still need you, captain.
进取号和心大星号不太一样
The Enterprise isn't quite like the Antares.
控制心大星号很容易
Running the Antares was easy.
你们最好友善点
You have to be nice.
知道吗？
All right?
史波克
Mr. Spock.
我的腿
My legs.
断掉了
They're broken.
查理，也放了他
Let him go too, Charlie.
- 为什么？ - 因为我要你放了他
- Why? - Because I'm telling you to.
因为你需要我操纵这艘星舰，而我需要他
Because you need me to run the ship, and I need him.
如果你再想伤害我
If you try to hurt me again,
我会让更多的人消失
I'll make a lot of people go away.
贾尼丝文书怎么样了？
And what about Yeoman Janice?
她死了，还是消失了，还是被毁灭了？
Is she dead, gone, destroyed?
我不会告诉你的
I won't tell you.
长大也没什么了不起的
Growing up isn't so much.
我不是大人，照样可以做任何事
I'm not a man, and I can do anything.
你却不行
You can't.
[空气系统]
我来启动力场，你可以回去了
I'll activate the force field myself. You can return to your section.
他表情很恶心
He had a mean look.
所以我把他定住了
I had to freeze him.
我喜欢高兴的表情
I like happy looks.
你们不进来吗？
Aren't you coming in?
这可不好
That wasn't nice.
你们会后悔的
You'll be sorry.
等着瞧吧，你们会后悔这么做的
You wait, you'll see. You'll be sorry you did that.
一定会后悔的
You will.
不
No.
不准笑！
No laughing!
寇克舰长，我的仪器显示
Captain Kirk, my instruments show
我们正在接收来自子空间频率3的
we're receiving a message on subspace frequency three,
舰对舰通讯信息
ship to ship.
但我听不到，长官
I can't hear it, sir.
查理，你是在发讯息还是在阻挡我们接收那条讯息？
Are you creating that message, or are you blocking one that's coming in?
舰长，这是我的游戏，你自己去想吧
It's my game, captain. You have to find out.
正如你所说的，游戏就是这么玩的
Like you said, that's how the game's played.
现在归你了，我已经把航线又锁定回5号殖民地了
You can have it now. I've locked on course for Colony V again.
我等的够长了，我要拿下他
I've waited long enough. I'm gonna take him on.
你对他没有任何特殊的抵抗力，不再有了
You don't have any special immunity. Not anymore.
把他逼急了，他会让你也消失的
Push far enough, he'd send you off to oblivion too.
- 史波克？ - 没可能的
- Mr. Spock? - Out of the question.
等一等
Wait a minute.
查理他…
Is Charlie--?
不对，等等，史波克
No, wait. Spock,
他接管星舰之后，有谁消失了吗？
has he done away with anybody since he took over?
就我们所知，没有
Not so far as we know.
说不定他办不到了
Then maybe he can't.
他可能达到极限了
Could be he's overreached himself.
这艘舰船很大，他已经全盘控制了
It's a big ship. He's taken full control.
如果我们可以加重他的负担
If we could tax his power,
把船上的每个装置、每条电路、每盏灯都打开
turn on every device on the ship, every circuit, every light, all of it.
在他应付这些东西的时候
And while he's fighting that,
我从旁让他分心，你们就可以给他打镇定剂
if I could distract him, maybe you could tranquilize him
控制住他
and keep him under
直到我们到达5号殖民地
until we reach Colony V.
很冒险，吉姆
Risky, Jim.
如果不试试，麦考伊，他会让我们所有人都消失
If we don't try, doctor, he'll get rid of us anyway.
别无选择，先生们，完全没有
There's no choice, gentlemen, none at all.
只要我想让你们消失，你们就会消失
I can make you all go away, any time I want to.
从我的椅子上下来，查理，马上下来
Get out of my chair, Charlie, and get out of it now.
你的船在我手里，舰长
I've got your ship, captain.
或许吧，查理
Maybe, Charlie,
但我觉得你没法掌控更多
but I don't think you can handle any more.
我觉得你已经到极限了，多一样都不行
I think you've reached your limit and can't take on one more thing.
但你却不得不这样做
But you're gonna have to.
我早可以让你消失，但我没有
I could have sent you away before, but I didn't.
那就干掉我啊
You're gonna have to take me on.
别逼我这么做
Don't make me do it now.
你抢了我的船，我现在要把它夺回来
You've got my ship, and I want it back.
我要我的船员回来，所有的
I want my crew back, whole...
就算是非得拧断你的脖子才能做到
...if I have to break your neck to do it.
不要逼我
Don't push me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉，但是…
I'm sorry, but...
住手
Stop it.
我叫你们住手！
I said, stop it!
舰长，导航控制台的障碍已经清除了
Captain, navigation console is clear now.
星舰对舵轮也有反应了
The ship is answering the helm.
长官，我们的右舷船头前方有不明物体
Sir, something off our starboard bow.
讯息说他们来自塔索斯星
The message says they're from Thasus.
不
No.
- 舰长，我怎么会？ - 已经没事了，文书
- Captain, how did I...? - It's all right, yeoman.
传感器显示那儿有不明物体
Sensors show there's something there.
偏导仪显示没有实体
Deflectors indicate no solid substance.
不！
No!
噢，不，求你了
Oh, no, please.
别让他们把我带走
Don't let them take me.
我无法忍受再跟他们一起生活了！
I can't live with them anymore.
你们是我的朋友
You're my friends.
你们说过是我的朋友，记得吗？
You said you were my friends, remember?
在我刚来的时候！
When I came aboard!
求求你
Please.
我要回家
I wanna go home.
带我回家
Take me home.
几个世纪前，我已经抛弃了我的形体
I have taken my form centuries ago
以至于需要这样我才能和你们交流
so that I may communicate with you.
意识到这个孩子跑了，已经太迟了
We did not realise until too late that the boy had gone,
致使第一艘舰船的全体船员丧命，我们对此感到非常痛心
and we are saddened that his escape cost the lives of the first ship.
我们帮不了他们
We could not help them,
但已经把你们的人和船都归还给你了
but we have returned your people and your ship to you.
一切如初
Everything is as it was.
我不会再这么做了
Oh, I won't do it again.
求你了，我会听话的，我不会再这么做了
Please, I'll be good. I won't ever do it again.
心大星号的事是我的错，对不起
I'm sorry about the Antares.
真的很抱歉！
I'm sorry!
求你让我留在船上！
When I came aboard!
求你们了
Please.
我想和你一起走
I want to go with you.
帮帮我
Help me.
这个孩子属于他自己的种族
The boy belongs with his own kind.
不可能
That will be impossible.
我们会教他在我们的社会中生活
We can teach him to live in our society.
如果他可以学会不使用他的超能力
If he can be taught not to use his power.
我们给了他超能力让他能够生存下来
We gave him the power so he could live.
他总会使用它的
He will use it, always.
他会毁灭你和你的种族
And he would destroy you and your kind,
不然你就得杀了他，来拯救你们自己
or you would be forced to destroy him to save yourselves.
没有其他办法了吗？
Is there nothing you can do?
我们给了他生命
We offer him life.
所以我们会照顾好他的
And we will take care of him.
来吧，查理
Come, Charles.
求求你
Oh, please.
别让他们带走我
Don't let them take me.
我根本就无法触摸到他们！
I can't even touch them!
贾尼丝
Janice.
他们没有感觉
They can't feel.
不像你
Not like you.
他们不会去爱！
They don't love!
求你了
Please.
我想留下来
I want to stay.
留下来，留下，留…
Stay, stay, stay...
查理已经回到塔索斯人的船上了，长官
Charlie's back onboard the Thasian ship, sir.
他们发讯号说他们离开了
They signalled they're leaving.
没事的，文书
It's all right, yeoman.
已经结束了
It's all over now.
本集结束
谢谢观赏